# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天我要上去弄一下上面的竹叶
Today I am going up there to clean up the bamboo leaves
# 然后再把我们那个梨 已经这么大了用纸包起来
And then cover our pears, which are like this big now, with paper bags
# 要不然那些小鸟几下就给它吃掉了
Otherwise the birds will eat the pears very quickly
# 第一次上去还多害怕
I was a little scared the first time I climbed up here
# 扫不扫哦
Are we sweeping the roof?
# 要扫
Yes
# 既然上去了肯定要扫了
Of course, he is sweeping it, he climbed up there after all
# 吓我一跳 差点滑了
I almost slipped and got scared a little
# 现在终于上来了 用我四伯爷给我的这个袋子
Finally I am up here now, using the bags my uncle gave me
# 然后把这个梨全部套起来
To cover all the pears
# 这个鸟啊 梨小的时候它不吃
These birds do not eat the pears when they are small
# 就是专门等到它长到半大不熟的时候吃得干干净净的
Birds purposely wait until the pears grow half way through, then they will eat all the pears
# 上都上来了然后我先把这个竹叶扫一下
Since I am up here, I am going to sweep the bamboo leaves
# 这个竹叶太多了
There are too many bamboo leaves up here
# 打击看一下这个梨 这个已经很大个了
Take a look at this pear, it is pretty big now
# 已经这么大了
It has grown a lot
# 这现在就是小鸟要吃的时候了
This is the time when birds are going to eat the pears
# 这个已经被梨压下来了 等一下我用一个（袋子）
Now the weight of the pears is pulling the branch down, I am going to use (a bag to collect them)
# 掉了一个
One fell off
# 都已经这么大太可惜了
It has grown pretty big, what a pity
# 待会儿用个东西把它撑起来
I am going to find something to support it
# 这个掉在上面已经烂了这个
It has fallen and become rotten on the roof
# 太可惜了
What a waste
# 这个都已经烂了
This one is rotten
# 梨太多了把这个压垮了
There are too many pears up here and the weight is dragging down the branches
# 废了九牛二虎之力把这个上面又扫了
It took so much effort to sweep the roof again
# 我估计十天半个月之后又是一层
I estimate that after a couple of weeks, it will be another layer of bamboo leaves again
# 现在我来包一下这个梨
Now I am going to cover the pears
# 有没有懂行的 来教我一下
Is there any expert here that can teach me something about this?
# 这个位置
Put it here?
# 嗯 可以了
Yes, this is good
# 有没有懂行的教我一下这个怎么弄
Is there any professional here that can teach me how to get this done?
# 在我没学会之前先让它这样子吧
I will just leave it like this before I learn how to handle it
# 这个撑哪里 撑这里差不多
Where do I put this one? Should I put it here?
# 可以
Okay this is good
# 这边再给它撑一个就差不多了
Then I will put another one here, it should fine now
# 好
Okay
# 这个给它打开
Now I am opening this bag
# 这给它打开 然后把这个果子放进去
Open the bag then put the pear into the bag
# 然后这样子收这个 收收收
And then wrap it up and pinch together the edge
# 收到这里的时候这有一根铁丝
At the end there's an iron wire to tie up
# 把它这样子捆起来捏紧就可以了 特别简单
Wrap up the edge and pinch the wire, then I am done. Very simple
# 一次装它两个 让它们有伴 稍微捏一下就可以了
I am bagging these two together, so they can keep each other company. Just slightly pinch it
# 这样鸟儿就不知道里面有梨 它就吃不到了
This way, the birds do not know there are pears in there, they cannot eat them
# 这里还有
There are more here
# 大家可以看一下这里上面有2个 这就是被鸟儿吃掉的
Let us take a look at the two up there, these are the ones that birds ate
# 可能说这个鸟儿想留着下一次来吃其它的
Maybe the birds wanted to come back and eat other pears
# 我这次就把它包起来
But I will cover the pears this time
# 哇这个上面 一枝上面结4个
Wow look at this, there are 4 pears on this branch
# 这个你搞得我好为难啊
What should I do with it?
# 我这么接呢
How do I cover them?
# 它们4个包在一起 4兄弟很棒
I will jut bag the four of them together. Four siblings, very nice
# 去年这个（树）上面都只长了几个
Last year, this (tree) only had a few pears
# 刚好要吃的时候就被鸟吃了
Birds ate most of the pears when the pears were about to ripe
# 今年给它保护一下
This year I am providing protection for the pears
# 这个是掉在那个（雨棚）上面
This one fell on top of that (shed)
# 被掉下来的竹叶捂在一起捂烂了 太可惜了丢掉
These pears were covered by the fallen bamboo leaves and got rotten. I have to throw them away, what a waste
# 把这个没烂的也包一下
I am going to cover this one that is not rotten
# OK
OK
# 这边可能它会烂就留点给鸟吃
This is probably going to rot, so I will just leave it to the birds
# 这几个特别漂亮
These pears look very nice
# 先包这两个
First cover these two
# 然后再包这两个
Then cover these two
# 哟 还包不住它啊
Oops, it does not fit the pear
# OK 可以了
Okay, this is good
# 好 那些包不到的不整了 不关事
You don't need to cover those that are too far to reach. Doesn't matter
# 那儿不好弄得 我逮要把它逮下来
It is not easy to reach them, I will try to pull them down
# 我看一下拉不拉得下来
Let me see if I can get it down
# 我四伯爷说的就这三个
These are the three my uncle was talking about
# 哎呦 包的不是很好 希望鸟吃不到
I did not cover them very well, so I hope the birds cannot reach them
# 看一下 我给你们看一下这个被鸟吃掉的
Here, let me show you the one that got eaten by the birds
# 看到没这个给它吃空了
Can you see that the inside is hollow, all eaten by the birds
# 这边是很好看的
On this side, it looks nice
# 浪费
Wasteful
# 我要下去了
I am going down now
# 本身想拍摄新影片，但第二天居然停电了！
I wanted to film new video, but we had a power outage the next day
# 就是我们去年买了一个发电机
We bought a generator last year
# 放了整整差不多一年了 今天终于派上用场了
We put it there for almost one whole year, finally we get to utilize it
# 因为我们县城现在停电
Because the county is experiencing a power outage
# 所以我要把这个发电机拿上去
So I am taking this generator up
# 把这个电给供上 然后我们才可以剪视频
So it can provide power for us to edit the video
# 我来先试一下这个行不行
Let me try to see if it works
# 还可以 用得了 没想到放这么久也还可以
Okay, it works. It is surprising that it still works after such a long time
# 还有桶油 油把它拿着
Oh and the gas, I need to take the gas with me
# 把这个油也给它带上
I need to take the gas as well
# 这发电机可能不轻 有一百斤吧应该有
The generator is not light. Probably at least 100 jin (50 kg)
# 然后把这个楼梯也带上
Also I need to take the ladder with me
# 这应该没问题 掉不下来
This should be fine, it won’t fall off
# 楼梯 发电机 灯差不多了
Ladder, generator and the light, this should be all
# 还有最重要的线都没拿 等一下拿去估计要翻车啊
We almost forgot the most important things, the cables. Almost failed to grab everything
# 这线我们配的是50米的
The cable is 50 meters long
# 还有把这些设备也拿上去
We might as well take all the equipment with us
# 差不多了 走嘛
Okay, this should be it, let’s go
# 好了 现在我们要回富顺了
Okay now we are heading back to Fushun
# 就是回去把这个发电机装上
Going back to put up the generator
# 然后继续剪我的视频
Then I will continue to edit my videos
# 还有就是这段时间在忙新工作室这边的事情
Moreover, lately I have been busy renovating my new studio
# 很少拍做菜的视频
I couldn't film many cooking videos
# 这里兄弟姐妹们先谅解一下
Sorry about this, hope you guys can understand
# 过段时间就可以拍了
I can start filming again later
# 应该三五几天吧
Around three to five days
# 好了 我们终于把这个弄上来了
Okay now we finally brought this up here
# 现在来把它卸下来 把线牵上去就可以了
Now I just need to unload it from the car and connect it with the cable
# 好了
Okay
# 可以了先将就着用
Okay I will just use the generator
# 这个终于接上电了
Now we finally have power
# 这个发电机功率应该不够
This generator probably is not powerful enough
# 可能我们拖空调拖不起 只能拖几台电脑
It is not powerful enough to run the AC, it can only support a few computers
# 不过也够了
But this is enough
# 来电没
Do you have power?
# 来了电没
# 来了的 那样子可以了嘎
Okay, it looks like this works well
# 好 可以了电脑开了可以剪视频了
Okay, the computer is on, I can edit video now
# 好了 本期视频到这里 拜拜
Okay, this is the end of the video, bye